Co Andre
Williams thank you Mr Speaker I Rise to
take a call on behalf of New Zealand
first on the insurance credential
supervision Amendment Bill and New
Zealand first will be supporting this
bill we believe that it is vitally
important uh that the fundamental
situation New Zealand that we must have
a sound well functioning Insurance
sector it has been clearly proven over
recent years during our major natural
disasters unless we do New Zealand is at
Great risk it is most important I think
all parties in this house would agree
that we must have a robust Insurance
sector with substance and that of course
includes our own eqc earthquake uh
commission the Ins Insurance sector
underpins the basics of our modern
economy if we do not have a sound
Insurance sector our whole economy could
well suffer the public must have
confidence that this sector is sound and
appropriate credential supervision of
the sector is an important regulatory
function that this Parliament must
insurers done to the very highest level
the CH earthquakes demonstrated the
critical role of insurance and it
highlighted some concerns as were
Illustrated in the situation with AMI it
would be so easy for situations like
that to occur if there was no not
oversight by this Parliament and by the
government to ensure that the right
safeguards are put in place in terms of
the insurance
sector but the major disasters also
revealed some aspects of the insurance
Insurance sector that may not be working
optimally for New Zealand with so much
of the insurance sector dominated by
overseas companies it is essential that
the regulatory framework is
comprehensive up toate and that it works
well New Zealand first appreciates the
significance of the insurance sector
that it operates well in New Zealand and
that it at and that at this present time
we do seem to have it well and truly in
hand that is not to say that things
cannot fall through the cracks however
this bill goes a long way to tidy up
areas such as that but New Zealand first
does have a few questions such as uh the
financial standards not being required
of the insurance provider if it is in a
runoff period if the licensed insur
assur is described as being in a state
of runoff and is not entering into new
contracts for insurance The Reserve Bank
will be satisfied that it does not
therefore have to have a Current
financial strength rating we do have
some concerns about that and we would
welcome the Minister of Finance and the
government explaining this a little
further because we believe that the
highest Financial ratings should be
required even at a time when an
insurance company is running down in New
Zealand we would not want an insurer to
slip out the back door because its
Financial ratings were not held to the
highest level throughout its activities
in New Zealand the insurance credential
supervision Amendment bill is very much
an administrative bill it is a technical
bill bill it tidies up areas through the
Reserve Bank to make sure that our
insurance industry in New Zealand has
better governance and better oversight
New Zealand first will be supporting
this bill as we do believe it takes
positive steps for improved controls
over the insurance industry and will
enhance the effectiveness of the act so
New Zealand first will be supporting
it a call John he Mr Speaker caller
tidying up calling